lyricstraining.com 2018-06-24

# Privacy Policy | LyricsTraining

##### Last Updated: May 24, 2018

## 1\. General

LyricsTraining is a service for learning languages in a fun and innovative way through music, videos and song lyrics.

Both the website [https://lyricstraining.com](https://lyricstraining.com/) with all its variants and subdomains, as well as the app with the same name (<https://lyricstraining.com/app>) available for Android and iOS devices, are owned by ELASTHINK, S.L. (hereinafter " **Elasthink** ") located at Calle Fuerteventura 9, Alovera, 19208, Guadalajara, Spain.

In **Elasthink** , we take your privacy very seriously, for this we use all the necessary technical and human means to make sure they do not fall into the wrong hands. Under no circumstances will we give your information to third parties without your consent.

Recently we modified our Privacy Policy to make it easier for our users to understand, in compliance with the new European **General Data Protection Regulation** ([GDPR](https://www.eugdpr.org/)) which comes into effect on May 25, 2018.

Access and use of the website or the app imply that the user has read and accepted this entire Privacy Policy, as well as the terms and conditions of use that can be viewed at the following address: <https://lyricstraining.com/terms>.

Below we describe the data we collect, for what purpose and how it is handled, as well as the procedure so you can exercise your right to change or delete data.

If you have any queries, you can contact us at the following email address: [support@lyricstraining.com](mailto:support@lyricstraining.com)

## 2\. What personal data do we collect?

To access the service, we request the minimum information required.

We will never use this information for purposes other than those described here, and you will always have the option to delete your account and all your data permanently, when you think it is appropriate.

### 2.1 User registration

It is not necessary to register to access the website, although it is recommended so you can enjoy all features of the service. In contrast, to access the app, it is mandatory to be registered.

These are the data we request to register you and create a new user account:

#### Username

We use your username or pseudonym, so we can communicate with you and for displaying your score in the high score tables.

**NOTE** : The username is unique, and it is currently not possible to change it once registration is complete.

#### Email

We need your email to be able to identify you and to contact you later, for example to confirm registration or to send you important notifications on your service activity and usage.

**NOTE** : We will never use your email to send you unwanted messages, spam or advertising, and in no circumstances will we give your information to third parties.

#### Password

To access the service with your username or email we need to verify your identity through a password that we will ask you to register.

This password is sent securely and stored fully encrypted so that nobody, inside or outside our organization, can decrypt it.

**NOTE** : If you access through Facebook it is not necessary to enter a password, instead an identifier provided by Facebook is saved to simplify access.

#### Country

We ask you to indicate your country of origin or residence, so we can display the corresponding flag next to your username in the high score tables. This also allows you to filter and view the scores of users from the same country as you.

#### Gender

We ask you to indicate your gender (male or female) to be able to address you correctly and to select the corresponding default generic image accordingly.

#### Date of birth

You are required to indicate your date of birth, so we can verify your age and restrict access to inappropriate content.

#### Teachers (only on the website)

To enable access to functions specially designed for teachers, such as the creation of customized exercises, it is necessary you identify yourself as a teacher.

#### Access through Facebook

When accessing through Facebook or linking your account later, we save the identifier provided by Facebook and use your profile picture for your LyricsTraining account.

### 2.2 Activity record

When using our service, we store all the information on your activity, the games that you play as well as your best scores.

Other users can see your scores when they are among the top ones.

### 2.3 Content provided by users

You can collaborate with us by adding new content from the " **My Lyrics** " section of the website using our integrated editor.

To do this, you must select a video, then add and synchronize the song’s lyrics or the direct transcription of the video, along with extra information such as title, artist, genre, etc.

The videos and lyrics added are carefully reviewed by our team to ensure the quality of the content and to exclude inappropriate content.

The lyrics are the exclusive property of the authors and the owners of their rights (copyright), who can request their removal from the website or the app at any time. Under no circumstances are they the property of the users who share the content.

In 2015, Elasthink settled an agreement with the major music publishers to authorize the use of lyrics on our website and the app. For more information, contact us.

The videos are provided by the YouTube video platform through its " **Embeddable Player** ", with the consent of the authors and owners who allow these videos to be viewed outside the YouTube.com domain.

Elasthink does not store all or part of the videos, nor does it process any of the data transferred while they are playing.

If you are the author or owner of the rights of any lyric or video and you wish to request its removal or modification, you can contact us at the following email address: [copyright@lyricstraining.com](mailto:copyright@lyricstraining.com)

### 2.5 Other data

At present, the following functionality is only available on the website:

#### My favorites

The user can add and delete their favorite lyrics.

#### Customized exercises (only for teachers)

Teachers can create customized exercises by selecting the words for students to fill out and then share these exercises with them.

## 3\. Where and how are these data stored?

Your data is stored in a database managed by the company Amazon Web Services, Inc. with the tightest security measures in a data center located in Dublin, Ireland.

Amazon Web Services, Inc. is a provider of a diverse range of on demand technology services and computing resources that is backed by a broad global infrastructure and extensive experience.

For more information, see the following links:  
<https://aws.amazon.com/service-terms>  
<https://aws.amazon.com/privacy>  

## 4\. How can these data be viewed, modified or deleted?

To consult and modify your personal and access data, you can access the " **My Account** " section from the user menu, both on the website and in the app.

To completely erase your account and all the stored data, you will find the option " **Delete Account** " at the end of the " **My Account** " section; this is only available on the website.

You can also contact us at the support address: [support@lyricstraining.com](mailto:support@lyricstraining.com)

## 5\. Use of cookies

A cookie is a small piece of information sent by a website that is stored temporarily on the user's computer or mobile device.

We use cookies and equivalent technologies to store basic information for running the service, such as the session identifier or the selected language of preference.

If you want to avoid the storage of this information, you can disable the use of cookies in your browser, however it is not recommended as they are essential for the smooth functioning of the service.

## 6\. IP Address of users

Elasthink does not store or carry out any specific handling of the IP address with which users access the service in such a way that it can be associated to or identify a given physical individual. Besides, the IP address may not be the same each time and different users may share the same address.

## 7\. Third party services

### 7.1 Youtube

All the videos that are displayed on our website and in the app are provided directly by the YouTube video platform through its " **Embeddable Player** ". Under no circumstances do we store or perform any treatment of the transferred data.

YouTube LLC is a company of Google Inc.

For more information, consult your terms of service and data privacy:  
<https://www.youtube.com/terms>  
<https://policies.google.com/privacy>  

## 7.2 Google Analytics

To analyze and improve the usage made by our website or app users, we use Google Analytics, a service provided by Google Inc.

In LyricsTraining, we have activated the anonymity of the data collected by Google Analytics, so your IP address will be abbreviated.

Google Analytics uses the cookies mentioned earlier.

You can find more information at the following links:  
<https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html>  
<https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en>  

## 7.3 DoubleClick for Publishers

DoubleClick for Publishers is a service provided by Google Inc. that allows you to manage advertising on websites and carry out advertising campaigns in combination with the use of external advertising networks.

This service uses cookies to track the behavior of users and improve the advertising that is shown to the user based on their interests and preferences.

To disable the use of cookies or to change the settings for personalizing ads, see the following link: [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/)

**NOTE** : Elasthink does not share your personal data with any provider or advertising network whatsoever.

## 8\. Changes to this privacy policy

This Privacy Policy may undergo changes in the future, so we recommend you review it regularly.

When these changes are sufficiently relevant according to our criteria, we will notify you through a notice when accessing the service or by sending an email to the address associated with your user account.

By continuing to access or use our service, we understand that the user is satisfied with the changes made.
